Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.4 绿色软件联盟www.xdowns.com
Build time 09.12.21 10:05:48
-== 字幕制作：Meky ==- -== 校对&时间轴: Meky ==-
（以下影片描述《超人第二集》
当初构思及筹划开拍的过程
有些片段来自划面测试中 我们无法拍摄的桥段）
（这部电影是用以纪念 克里斯多夫李维
没有他，我们绝不会相信人类能飞）
I ask you now to pronounce judgment...
我要求你们念出
...on those accused.
判决的内容
On this...
对这些被告
This mindless aberration, whose only means of expression...
对这个无情的叛离者 他只想以暴力和破坏
...are wanton violence and destruction.
来表现其情感
On the woman, Ursa...
对这个女人亚莎K
...whose perversions and unreasoning hatred of all mankind...
她对所有全体人类的 曲解及不合理的仇恨心态
...have threatened even the children of the planet Krypton.
已经威胁到 全体氪星的儿童
Finally, General Zod.
最后一位是查德将军
Chief architect of this intended revolution...
创造者希望对这种预谋
...and author of this insidious plot to establish a new order amongst us...
重新建立一项秩序所作之革命 加以摧毁
...with himself as absolute ruler.
好让自己仍然成为 绝对之统治者
The decision of the council will now be heard.
现在宣布判决的结果
Guilty.
有罪
- Guilty. - Guilty.
-有罪 -有罪
Guilty.
有罪
The vote must be unanimous, Jor-EI.
本项表决具有敌意，乔艾尔
It has therefore now become your decision.
现在已经变成你的判决
You alone will condemn us if you wish...
如果你希望的话 你就判我们有罪吧
...and you alone will be held responsible by me.
那你就要对我这件事负责了
You will bow down before me, Jor-EI.
你会在我面前屈服的，乔艾尔
I swear it.
我发誓！
No matter that it takes an eternity, you will bow down before me!
不管天长地久 你终会在我面前屈服的
Both you...
你们两个
...and then one day...
将来K
...your heirs!
还有你的子孙
You will bow down before me!
你会在我面前屈服的！
- Forgive me! - I'll be back!
-原谅我 -我会回来的
Forgive me!
原谅我
Your mother Lara has sent you three blankets, of red, yellow and blue.
你母亲诺拉寄给你 红、黄、蓝，三条毯子
Their protection will ensure your strength.
它们能保护你，确保你的力量
It's kryptonite, Superman. A little souvenir from the old hometown.
是氪石，超人 从古老家乡来的纪念品
You were great in your day, Superman. But it just stands to reason...
你是很厉害，超人 不过应该是K
...when it came time to cash in your chips...
要收拾你的时候了
...this old, diseased maniac...
这位老而有病的疯子
...would be your banker.
将成为你的主宰
Mind over muscle.
小心肌肉过度紧绷
Why did you kiss me first?
你为何先吻我？
It... I didn't think you'd let me later.
我觉得你待会儿不会让我吻你
Stand aside, now.
站一边去
Free!
自由了！
主演：金哈克曼
主演：克里斯多夫李维
主演：马龙白兰度
片名：超人第二集
主演：奈德比提
主演：贾基库伯
主演：莎拉道格拉斯
主演：犸歌基德
主演：杰克欧哈洛伦
主演：梵乐莉派琳
主演：克里夫顿詹姆斯
EG马歇尔饰演总统
主演：马克麦克卢尔
主演：泰伦斯史坦普
故事：马里欧普柔
编剧：马里欧普柔
编剧：大卫纽曼 与雷斯利纽曼
制片：皮尔史班葛
导演：李察唐纳
Nice fresh melons. Nice fresh melons. Get them fresh here.
新鲜哈密瓜！非常新鲜的哈密瓜 要买新鲜就在这里
Good for the cooking, huh? Look at this, the best.
用来烹饪也很好喔 你看看，最好的
"Lex Luthor's scheme bombs. Superman saves nation.
雷克斯路瑟的炸弹阴谋 超人拯救国家
Master criminal draws harsh sentence. Exclusive story by Lois Lane.
犯罪之王被判重刑 露薏丝莲恩独家报导
Photographs by James Olsen."
吉姆欧森摄影
Luthor, you never looked lovelier.
雷克斯路瑟 你看起来永远这么邪恶
Lois, terrific job.
露薏丝，做得好
- Thanks, chief. - Great story, really great.
-谢了，老编 -非常好的报导，非常好
Hey, good morning, chief. You're late.
早安，老编，你迟到了
Yeah, Miss Lane, that's a great story. One of the best.
莲恩小姐，这故事很棒 是最棒的之一
Well, Jimmy, usually a picture isn't worth a thousand words when I write the story...
吉姆，通常一张照片 不值得我写一千字
...but in this case, congratulations.
但以这则报导来说，恭喜你
- Yeah, thanks a lot. - Yeah.
-多谢了 -是啊
There's Mr. Kent. Bet he wishes he'd been around when it all happened.
肯特先生来了，我赌他希望 事件发生时他能在场
Clark, he's never around when Superman appears.
超人出现时克拉克都不在场
Poor guy.
可怜的家伙
（揭开超人的秘密）
- You got a page in the front? - Yeah.
-头版还有位置吗？ -有
Miss Lane got the best story.
莲恩小姐有绝对正点的报导
Good morning, Lois.
早安，露薏丝
Hi.
嗨
Lane, Kent, get in here!
莲恩、肯特，进来
Now, see, Jimmy, you got me in trouble.
看吧，吉姆，你害我有麻烦了
- We were talking. - So long. A big mistake.
-我们刚刚正在谈话 -再见，是个天大的错误
Next time, don't do that to me.
下一次别这样对我
- Good morning, Lois. How are you today? - Oh, I'm just super. Thanks.
-早安，露薏丝，你今天好吗？ -非常好，谢谢
- Good morning, Mr. White. - I'm super.
-早安，白先生 -我很好
- Yeah, morning. You're late, Kent. - I know. I'm sorry, Mr. White.
-早安，你迟到了，肯特 -我知道，很抱歉，白先生
- I got stuck in traffic. - Oh, that's a new one.
-路上塞车 -又有新借口了
- Excuse me? - I mean, as opposed to:
-你说什么？ -我是说
"I was stuck in a phone booth" or "I got locked into the men's bathroom."
除了“我被卡在电话亭里”或 “我被锁在男厕里”之外
Lois, what are you talking about? I'm sorry I was late.
露薏丝，你在说什么？ 我很抱歉我迟到了
If you two wanna bicker, I have just the assignment for you.
你们想吵闹的话 我刚好有任务给你们
You're gonna pose as a honeymoon couple to get an expose on the newlywed racket.
你们要扮成蜜月小夫妻 参加一个新婚宴会
Some of those hotels are bilking those poor kids for every cent they can get.
有些饭店压榨这些可怜孩子 的微薄收入
Real human-interest stuff. Make your Aunt Hattie cry her eyes out.
是条令人感兴趣的新闻 保证那些婆婆妈妈痛哭流涕
- Newlyweds? - That is a great idea, Mr. White.
-新婚夫妇？ -这主意真棒，白先生
- I'm sorry, but I'm in the middle of a series... - I mean, it wouldn't take long.
-对不起，但我正在追踪一系列K -那不会花上你很多时间
We could just fly right up there and zoom back down again.
我们可以直接飞过去 再飞回来
No, Superman?
不好吗，超人？
Yeah. If he'd give you two a ride, maybe we could save a couple bucks.
对，要是他愿意载你们一程 也许我们能省下一些钱
I gotta see young Olsen. Six lousy photographs...
我要找小欧森，六张龌龊的照片K
...and that kid's hitting me up for a raise. - Excuse me. Mr. White? Could we talk?
-那小子还一直吵加薪 -抱歉，白先生，我们能谈谈吗？
Darn.
可恶
You look like the cat who swallowed the canary this morning.
你看起来像吞了一只金丝雀的猫
A canary? No, actually I was thinking of something bigger...
金丝雀？才不，是更大的东西
...something that flies, something more in blue.
一种会飞的、颜色更蓝的东西
Lois, as usual, I'm totally in the dark...
露薏丝 我和以往一样，身陷黑暗中K
Let me just turn on the lights for you then.
让我为你把灯点亮
Get the picture?
懂了吗？
I didn't put this together until this morning. Which is really strange...
我到现在才拼凑出全貌，真的蛮有趣的
...because a good reporter isn't supposed to let anything slip by her.
因为一名记者 绝不会忽略任何细节
Well, that's very amusing. Yes.
那很有趣，没错
- Excuse me. - Amusing?
-不好意思 -有趣？
- Yes, sirree, that's... That's very amusing. - Amusing, huh?
-是的，非常有趣 -有趣是吧？
Tall, broad shoulders...
高大、宽阔的肩膀
...dark hair.
深色头发
Gotta give you credit, you really had me fooled.
我得承认你伪装的很成功
And I'm nobody's fool...
我没有骗任何人
...Superman.
超人
Superman?
超人？
You mean you think I'm Superman?
你是说你以为我是超人？
- Willing to bet my life on it. - Lois, you know, you are priceless.
-我愿意用生命作赌注 -露薏丝，你知道吗？你是无价的
Really. That is the single most ridiculous thing I've ever...
真的，那是我知道最可笑的事了
- Lois, what are you doing? - You wouldn't let me die, Superman.
-露薏丝，你在做什么？ -你不会让我死的，超人
- Oh, God. - Help her out. Help her out.
-老天 -救她出来，救她出来
- Clark! - Lois, what have you done?
-克拉克 -露薏丝，你做了什么？
Clark, the... You're not...
克拉克，你不是K
Hey, Clark, you seen Lois?
克拉克，你有见到露薏丝吗？
She just stepped out for a minute.
她刚刚出去了
This is how it ends for the greatest criminal mind of our time.
这是本世代最伟大罪犯的下场
Not with a whimper, not with a bang.
没有人哭也没有人闹
How do they choose to reward Lex Luthor...
他们将如何纪念雷克斯路瑟
...the greatest genius in this world?
这位世上最伟大的天才？
Do they give him glory or treasure? What, matter of fact, do they give him?
他们给他荣耀还是宝藏？ 说实话，他们给了什么？
Life plus 25, Luthor. Get to work.
终生监禁外加ぼ五年，快工作！
Don't feel bad, Mr. Luthor. It almost worked.
别伤心，路瑟先生 你差点就成功了
I mean, California almost fell down, right in the ocean.
我说的是加州差点就沉入海底
Millions of people was almost killed.
百万人几乎丧命
If it hadn't been for that guy Superman, that overgrown Boy Scout.
如果不是超人 那个成长过度的男童军
- I want my Liberace record back tonight. - Tonight?
-今晚我将要回我的自由 -今晚？
What are you gonna do with a guy like that? He flies around so fast and everything.
那种人你要怎么对付？ 他飞那么快又什么都会
I mean, they can't even trace that guy on that radar they got.
甚至连雷达都无法追踪
Every time they try, he just flies off.
只要他们想追踪，他马上飞走
- Where? - North.
-往哪个方向？ -北方
Why?
为什么？
To ski?
为了去滑雪？
Otis, every man has his vulnerable point.
欧提斯，每个人都有弱点
Some, like you, Otis, have more than one.
像你这种人的弱点不止一个
I didn't see Superman's in time.
我没能及时看到超人
But now, through patience, invention, and skill...
现在借由耐心、创造力及技术
...my little black box is just about ready.
我的小黑箱就快完成了
Oh, that little black box in our cell?
我们囚房中的小黑箱
That little black box, Mr. Luthor...
那个小黑箱，路瑟先生
...what's it for?
那有什么用途？
That little black box goes beyond any normal, conventional radar.
那个小黑箱比传统雷达有用
It tracks alpha waves.
它能追踪阿尔发波
Alpha waves. Yeah.
阿尔发波
I could've said it tracked pasta e fagioli, couldn't I?
我可以说这模仿青豆面条，是吧？
Oh, with garlic, Mr. Luthor. And butter.
要加上大蒜和奶油，路瑟先生
Boy.
老天
Those alpha waves will take me north to his secret.
阿尔发波能引我到北极 到他的秘密
And when I have his secret, I'll have Superman.
当我知道超人的秘密 我就不怕他了
Slasher Fogelstein's a bed wetter.
屠杀者佛吉斯顿是个尿床小鬼
Slasher Fogelstein's a bed wetter. Pass it.
屠杀者佛吉斯顿是个尿床小鬼 传下去
Hi, Mr. Fogelstein.
你好，佛吉斯顿先生
- Too fast. Can you get the speed right?
太快了，你能用正常速度吗？
I told you, they installed those three weeks ago.
我告诉你，他们三周前就装好了
Hey.
嗨
You follow the bouncing ball for a while. Thing's giving me a headache.
你来监视一下这跳动符号 它让我头很痛
Anyway, somebody's gotta check up on those guys.
总之，派人去查看那些家伙
Yeah, I keep on forgetting about them.
说得对！我老是把他们忘了
How long they been up there, 45 days?
他们在上面多久了？45天？
The whole world's forgotten about it.
全世界都已将我们遗忘了
Houston calling Artemis II.
休士顿呼叫阿特蜜丝二号
Houston calling Artemis II. Come in.
休士顿呼叫阿特蜜丝二号 请回答
Morning, Houston. Hold on, Nate.
-早安，休士顿 -等一下，纳特
- Yo. - How are things going?
-喂！ -情况如何？
All systems normal, Houston.
一切系统都很正常，休士顿
Andy is out doing the geological survey.
安迪正在外面进行地质调查
More rocks. Nice.
更多石头
And cosmonaut Boris is getting some soil samples.
柯斯墨诺伯里斯正在采土样
By the way, Boris and I are engaged.
对了，伯里斯跟我订婚了
I had a feeling about you guys when I saw your Rorschach tests.
当我看到你的罗夏墨渍测验时 心中已经有数
Just a little detente humor there, Houston.
只是开玩笑舒缓一下，休士顿
Surface conditions unchanged?
表面状况没有改变吗？
Well, it's mighty pretty out there. Mighty...
外太空的景色非常美丽
...pretty. - Mighty pretty.
-非常美丽K -没错
Right.
对
Look, Nate?
听我说，纳特K
Nate, wake up, will you?
纳特，专心点好吗？
That's it. I'm dreaming.
没错，我是在作梦
Artemis, come in.
阿特蜜丝，请回答
Well, Houston, we seem to have an unidentified flying object.
休士顿 这里好像出现不明飞行物
Unidentified?
不明飞行物？
- What does it look like? - Well...
-它是什么样子？ -很像是K
...a lot like a girl.
一个女孩
You.
你
- What kind of a creature are you? - Just a man.
-你是何种生物？ -我是个男人
A man?
你是男人？
What a fragile sort of life form this is.
真脆弱的生命
Houston, come in. Come in, Houston.
休士顿，请回答，休士顿
Come in, Houston. Come in.
请回答，休士顿，请回答
Attempting manual liftoff.
尝试手动起飞
Can somebody hear me?
有人听到我吗？
Houston!
休士顿！
Come on.
快啊
Come on, Houston!
快点啊，休士顿！
Oh, no. No!
喔，不K
Somebody help me!
谁来救我
- Artemis, Houston calling. Come in. - What's going on?
-休士顿呼叫阿特蜜丝，请回答 -怎么回事？
- I don't know. We've lost contact. - So?
-我不知道，我们失去连系了 -所以呢？
Well, we really...
我说的是真的
Artemis, come in, please.
阿特蜜丝，请回答
All right, which one of you guys is using the hair dryer?
好了，你们谁在用吹风机？
Strange. I tore those metal fibers like paper.
好奇怪！ 那些金属我撕起来像在撕纸
And what he did was amazing.
而他的举动 真是太惊人了K
- Something is happening. - Yes, to all of us.
-有些改变发生了 -没错！我们三个都一样
The closer we come to an atmosphere with only one sun...
我们愈接近 只有一个太阳的大气层
...a yellow sun...
一个黄色的太阳K
...the more our molecular density gives us unlimited powers.
我们的分子密度愈大 也给予我们无穷的力量
They come from there.
他们来自那里
A place called Houston.
一个叫做休士顿的地方
Then we will go there too...
那么我们也去那里
...to rule.
去统治那个星球
Finally, to rule.
终于K能够统治星球了
Three-eighty-two, out.
382室，熄灯
Three-eighty-three, out.
383室，熄灯
Three-eighty-four, out.
384室，熄灯
Three-eighty-five, out.
385室，熄灯
Lights out, Luthor.
熄灯，路瑟
I said, lights out.
我叫你熄灯！
You guys are about 10 seconds away from solitary, you know that?
再十秒我就会进去找你们 听到了没有？
I told you to...
我叫你们K
Freeze, freeze.
不要动！不要动！
Mr. Luthor.
路瑟先生
- How we gonna get over that wall? - How'd we get in?
-我们要怎么越过那道墙？ -我们怎么进来的？
- We flew in here, remember? - That's how we'll get out.
-我们飞进来的，记得吗？ -那我们就飞出去
Oh, no, not that guy.
不，不是那家伙
Did you just go "psst"?
你刚刚叫我吗？
I wish I had, Mr. Luthor, before we left.
我希望我有，路瑟先生 在我们离开前
Not that "psst," that "psst."
不是那个，是那个
- Don't go "psst" when I go "psst." - You do it.
-当我这样时别那样 -你去做
Go out there and find it.
快出去找一找
- What am I looking for? - You'll know when you see it.
-我要找什么？ -你看到时就会知道
I think I found it.
我想我找到了
What is it?
这是什么？
It's a ladder, you dummy.
这是个楼梯，傻瓜
Hi, Miss Teschmacher.
黛丝犸克小姐，你好
Come on.
来
Hurry up. Hurry up.
动作快！
Come on, hurry.
快一点！
Otis, hold that ladder. Hurry up.
欧提斯，抓住楼梯！快点
- Yard line, touchdown! Oh, what a beautiful play.
码线，达阵！ 喔，打得真是太好了
But there's a marker downfield. It could be against...
不过裁判丢了手帕 它可能是某队犯规K
- Come up. - Come on.
-上来啊 -快点
Here I come, Mr. Luthor.
我来了，路瑟先生
- Get off. Get off. - Otis!
-下去，下去 -欧提斯！
- We're sinking! - Get off, get off!
欧提斯，我们在往下掉 下去！快下去！
Very good, Miss Teschmacher. Very good.
黛丝犸克小姐，你做得很好
- What am I doing here? Why am I here? - Miss Teschmacher...
-我来这里干嘛？我为什么在这里？ -黛丝犸克小姐K
...is this a philosophy seminar?
这是哲学课吗？
- No. This is a getaway. - No.
不，这是通道
- Getaway. - Right.
-通道？ -没错
It's ingenious. I don't know where you got the inspiration from.
这很天才 我不知道你哪儿来的灵感
I got it from you, Lex.
从你那里得来的，雷克斯
Hot air rises.
热气上升
Would you like to take a trip?
你想来趟旅行吗？
A trip? A vacation.
旅行？放大假吗？
Lex, I can go shopping. I can buy a bikini.
雷克斯，我可以去血拼 买件比基尼
You thought about me in a bikini while in prison?
你想要我在监狱里穿着比基尼？
No, I didn't, actually.
不，我其实没那么想
I thought about you in a parka.
我想的你是穿着毛皮外套
You thought about me in a parka?
我穿毛皮外套？
You are sick, Lex. You are really sick.
你很病态，雷克斯，你真的病了
That's possible.
有可能
North, Miss Teschmacher.
往北！黛丝犸克小姐
Due north.
正北方
Lex, north.
雷克斯，北方
That's what I said, due north.
就像我所说的，正北方
- That's what you said. - I know I said I said that.
-你的确说过 -我知道我说我说过了
- I just heard it. - Yes, Lex.
-我刚刚才听到 -对，雷克斯
Don't repeat what I say when I say something.
别重复我说的话
- I won't repeat what you say. - Okay, don't.
-我不会重复你说的话 -好，别重复就是
Well, stop repeating me.
别再重复我的话
（蜜月天堂饭店）
Excuse me.
对不起
Would you like to carry Mrs. Smith over the threshold?
你是否想抱着史密斯太太 进入门槛K
It's sort of traditional.
那是一种传统
I can give you a hand if you have trouble lifting.
如果你抱不动，我可以帮忙
- No, of course not. - Honey. Thanks, I'll walk.
不用了！当然不用 亲爱的，谢谢，我自己走
Certainly, dear.
没问题，亲爱的
Mush! Mush!
快跑！快跑！
I am mushing.
我已经在跑了
North, Miss Teschmacher.
往北！黛丝犸克小姐
- North, north! - Yes, Lex. North.
-往北，往北！ -是的，雷克斯，往北
Oh, you must be wrong, Lex. This couldn't be his home way up here.
你一定弄错了，雷克斯 这种地方一定不是他的家
"Wrong, Lex."
“你错了，雷克斯”
Miss Teschmacher, those are two words we do not use in the same sentence.
黛丝犸克小姐，那两个词 不能出现在同一个句子里
Well, it's funny there's no front door.
这很古怪，它没有大门
Miss Teschmacher, "funny" is a person trying to smile without any teeth.
黛丝犸克小姐 “古怪”是指有人不露齿而笑
Right.
是的
All right, come on, Lex. Come on.
好了，过来，雷克斯，过来
Move out of the way.
让开
- This way. - It's this way.
-这边 -是这边
Lex, it's this way.
雷克斯，是这边
It's this way, Lex.
是这边，雷克斯
- Come on. Come on. - Get off!
-来吧，来啊 -别碰我！
Come on.
来吧
- Fantastic. - Fantastic.
-太好了！ -太好了
It's fantastic!
真是好极了！
The construction goes far beyond any known architectural theory.
目前所知的建筑理论 都无法完成这栋建筑物
- It's beautiful. - It's beautiful.
-真的是很美 -很美
- Lex. - I'll be all right.
-雷克斯 -我没事的
No, me.
不，是我
Why can't you be more careful?
你为什么不能更小心一点？
- It's beautiful. - Beautiful.
-真的是很美 -很美
- It has everything. - Wrong.
-这里什么都有 -错了
- Why didn't you go before we left? - That was two days ago.
-我们出发前，你为何不去上？ -那是两天前的事了
Be careful, Lex.
小心点，雷克斯
Get...!
别碰K
Frankly, I think this place is a little boring. It's all white.
坦白说我觉得这地方有点无聊 到处一片洁白
Why doesn't the guy put up some pictures?
这家伙赶嘛不放些照片上去？
Maybe some bullfighting posters.
或许可以放些斗牛海报
- Don't touch anything. - Don't touch anything.
-什么都别碰 -什么都别碰
- Ice. - I said, don't touch it.
-是冰 -我说过别碰它
- It's not ice. - It looks like a crystal.
-这不是冰 -看起来像是水晶
The virtuous spirit has no need for thankful approval...
正直的灵魂 不需要别人的感谢K
- What the...? ...owning a certain conviction...
-搞什么？ -来获得一些肯定K
...that what has been done is right.
确定自己做的那件事是对的
That's the old man. He looks just like the kid.
这就是他老爸 他看起来跟超人很像
- Are you the old man? - Ask him where the bathroom is.
-你就是老爸吗？ -问他厕所在哪里？
Develop such conviction in yourself.
你必须靠自己来肯定
Are you here?
你在吗？
- The human heart on your planet... - He's not here.
-在你的星球上的人心 -他不在这里
It's a voice from the past. That's cute. That's really cute. Nice.
这声音来自过去，真聪明！
Lies, monstrous deceptions.
谎言，骇人听闻的诡计
So much for moral rearmament.
真会说教
Give me another crystal.
给我另一块水晶
Education crystal 108. Earth culture.
第108号教育水晶，地球文化
A typical ode much loved by the people you will live among, Kal-EI.
这是地球人们 相当喜爱的一首词赋，凯尔
Trees by Joyce Kilmer.
乔尹斯基尔默讲述“树”
I think that I shall never see
我认为我永远不会看到
A poem as lovely as a tree.
一首如树木般美丽的诗
Come on, I like trees.
别这样，我喜欢树木
So does your average cocker spaniel. Give me another.
你那只柯卡猎犬也一样 再给我另外一个
Cute.
真好笑
My son...
我的儿子K
- The man never ages. - Never ages.
-他长生不老 -长生不老
...the time has come to tell you of the darkest episode in Krypton history.
是该告诉你我们星球历史中 的黑暗时期了
- Now, this I wanna hear. - Unfortunately...
-这才是我想听的 -很不幸地K
...even on our peaceful planet...
即使在我们平静的星球上
...there have appeared once in a great while...
一些扰乱世界的元素
...certain antisocial elements.
依旧每隔一阵子出现一次
Deviants...
异常者
...what you call on Earth "criminals."
也就是地球上所说的罪犯
Criminals.
罪犯？
Deviants. He was right in the first place.
异常者，他一开始就说对了
Though of course, we are not a penalty planet like Earth...
虽然我们不像地球一样 是个苦难的星球
...and these unhappy souls were almost always successfully transformed...
这些不快乐的灵魂 几乎全数成功转换为K
...into productive citizens. - You never heard of Lex Luthor?
-奉公守法的市民 -你没听过雷克斯路瑟吗？
There were, however, three exceptions... Only three.
只有三者例外，只有这三者
- Who proved impossible to rehabilitate.
证明了自己不可能脱离邪恶
There's hope.
还有希望
Non, the destroyer.
零，是毁灭者
Unreasoning violence in the shape of a being.
以人类的形体进行无理由的暴力
Ursa. Vicious, cruel, obsessed by a single-minded hatred...
亚莎，邪恶又残忍
...which could never be determined.
一心被无法确定的仇恨驱使
And the one force that could unite them...
还有一股汇集他们的力量
...the only one whose warped genius could harness these forces of evil:
唯一能以他异常的聪颖 驾驭邪恶力量的人
General Zod.
查德将军
- He looks kind of cute. - His intended insurrection...
-他看起来满可爱的 -他意图叛乱
...was the most painful episode our people ever had to endure.
那是我们人民最痛苦的一段历史
But after a long and terrible battle...
在漫长恐怖的一役后
...peace and harmony were once again restored.
星球再次恢复和平与和谐
Kind of an anticlimax.
满令人扫兴的结局
We had, of course, no death penalty.
我们并没有死刑
Sensible enough.
非常合理
And so they were placed in the Phantom Zone...
他们因而被封印在幽灵区
...to be imprisoned for all eternity.
永远监禁他们
I do not know what could be done if they were to escape.
我们并不知道 若让他们逃走会有什么后果
On Krypton, these villains were uncontrollable.
在氪星 无法控制这些恶徒
On Earth, each of them would have the identical powers...
在地球上，他们每个人 都可能拥有强大的力量
...that you have.
跟你的力量完全一样
Think of it. Three super villains.
想想看！有三名超级恶徒
All three with the same power he has.
每个人的力量都跟他一样
All three totally dedicated to corruption, violence, evil.
每一位都具都有毁坏 暴力及邪恶倾向
They need a contact on Earth.
他们需要一位地球联络人
Someone who felt the same as they did, someone who...
和他们拥有同样感受的人
...had the same wonderful contempt for life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness.
某位与他们同样争取生命自由 并追求快乐的人
Too true to be good.
一位好的不可思议的人
Right?
对吗？
- Miss Teschmacher? - I found it.
-黛丝犸克小姐？ -我找到了
I think.
我想是
- Where's Jimmy Olsen when I need him? - Golly, isn't it beautiful?
-我需要吉姆时，他在哪里？ -风景真美，不是吗？
Yeah, it's gorgeous. Gorgeous.
太美了！美极了
- Lois? - Yeah?
-露薏丝 -什么事？
Look. Everybody's holding hands. Maybe we should hold hands too, huh?
你看，每个人都牵着手 或许我们也该牵手？
- Here's my hand, Clark. Hold it. - Thanks.
-克拉克，牵着我的手吧！ -谢谢
You know what? They're afraid to let go.
你知道吗？他们都不敢放手
- Why? - They let go, straight to the lawyer.
-为什么？ -因为他们一放手就会离婚
Oh, I don't know about that. They look kind of happy to me.
这点我并不清楚 我觉得他们看来都很快乐
That's because you're blind, Clark.
因为你视而不见，克拉克
- Oh, yeah. - Here.
-是吧！ -过来
- No, I've got it. No, l... - Yeah. Clark.
不用了，我戴着就行
You've gotta look after yourself. You've only got one pair of eyes.
你得好好照顾自己 你只有一双眼睛
- God. - Lois?
-天啊 -露薏丝
- Now, here. - Right.
-拿去 -是的
- Don't say I never did anything for you. - Thank you.
-别说我什么都没做K -谢谢
Son! Excuse me, please.
小子！对不起！
- Be careful. - What are you doing?
小心点！
Get down! Get down!
下来！快下来！
You embarrass me here in front of everybody.
你在众人面前害我丢脸
Lois, did you see what almost happened there? That little boy...
你看到差点出事了吗？ 那个小男孩K
Hey, I'm hungry. You hungry?
我饿了，你饿了吗？
- Lois, you're amazing. - Why, because I'm hungry?
-露薏丝，你真是不可思议 -因为我肚子饿？
No. Here you are standing in front of one of nature's most awesome spectacles...
不是，站在自然界中 最壮观的景色之前K
...and you're thinking about food. Aren't you impressed?
而你只想到要吃东西 难道你不为美景所震撼？
Clark, once a girl's seen Superman in action...
克拉克，当女孩子看过行动中的超人后
...Niagara Falls kind of leaves you cold, you know?
尼亚加拉瀑布只会让你觉得冷 你了解我的意思吗？
Him again, huh?
又是他
Oh, I'm sorry.
对不起
I have a one-track mind, don't I?
我的心胸很狭窄的吧
Well, my one-track mind is telling me that I'm hungry.
我狭窄的心胸告诉我，我饿了
- Hot dog? - Hot dog.
-吃热狗好吗？ -吃热狗
Hot dog.
热狗
Could I have some orange juice?
我还要柳橙汁
- Freshly squeezed. - Freshly squeezed, I know.
-现榨的 -现榨的，我知道
Hey, Mom. Look!
嘿，妈，你看！
Yeah, honey. That's nice.
亲爱的，你很棒
Okay, it's two mustard and relish, and...
好，我要两个加芥末和碎酸黄瓜的 还有K
Oh, my God!
我的天啊！
Help!
救命！
Somebody help!
快来人帮帮忙！
Do something!
快帮忙啊！
Good.
很好
Hey, Superman!
超人
Way to go, Superman!
干得好！超人
We got a great shot.
我们拍到一个好镜头
What a nice man. Of course he's Jewish.
真是个大好人
Incredible.
真不可思议
（迷雾之女四号）
- There you go. - Again, again!
-你到了 -再飞一次！再飞一次！
No, I'm sorry. Only one ride to a customer.
对不起，每个人只能飞一次
- Superman. Superman, it's me, it's Lois! - Bye.
-超人！超人，是我！露薏丝 -再见
Come here. You're gonna get it!
过来！我要好好修理你
- Give me a heart attack here. - It's me. It's Lois.
-你害我差点心脏病发作 -是我，露薏丝！
It's Lois Lane.
是露薏丝莲恩啊！
Well, hello and goodbye.
你好，再见
So this is planet Houston.
这就是休士顿星吗？
A very strange surface.
好奇怪的地表
- Oh, my gosh. - Oh, that's all right.
-我的天啊 -没关系
- I just didn't hear you knock, that's all. - Lois...
-我只是没听见你敲门，就这样 -露薏丝K
...the door wasn't even locked. Just anybody can walk in here.
门根本没锁，任何人都进得来
- There you go putting yourself down again. - Very funny.
-你又把自己比喻为凡人了 -很幽默
No, really, I'm serious.
不，我很认真
Well, anyway...
无论如何K
...here, a little something for the newlyweds' dinner tonight.
这是给今晚新婚晚宴的一点小东西
Pansies. Clark, how... How different.
是紫罗兰，克拉克 这很K很特别
Would you believe they grow wild all around here?
你相信它们在这儿 都是野生的吗？
You should see what they charge for roses at the gift shop.
你应该看看花店里玫瑰的价格
I'll bet, huh?
我想也是
- You know something, Lois? - What?
-你知道吗，露薏丝？ -什么？
Well, you know, in spite of the unreality of all this...
除了这件事的不真实感以外K
Well, you know, posing as newlyweds for the sake of a newspaper story.
你知道的 为了报导装扮成新婚夫妻
Well, in spite of myself even...
除了我自己甚至都K
...I'm kind of starting to feel like one in a way.
我开始觉得自己是其中之一了
- A newlywed, you? - I don't see why that should be so strange.
-新婚夫妻，你？ -我不觉得那有什么好奇怪
I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
抱歉，我不是那个意思
I mean, I'm sure there's thousands of girls who'd...
我是说 我确定有成千上万的女孩愿意K
Well, a few girls anyway.
至少有几个
- Go ahead and say it. - Say what?
-尽管说出来 -说什么？
That somehow you're not satisfied being here with me.
说你不满意和我一起待在这里
That in some way I don't seem to shape up very well in your eyes.
我在你眼里看来不太完美
I don't have anything to apologize for. I'm a good reporter.
我无需为任何事道歉 我是个好记者
No, I'm a very good reporter. And an even better friend to you.
不，我是个非常好的记者 还是你更好的朋友
- Stand up. - Stand up?
-站起来 -站起来？
Yeah, stand up, just for fun.
对，站起来，好玩嘛
Now, come here. Look at yourself. Just look at yourself.
过来这里，看看你自己 看看你自己
What we have here is a potentially aggressive, dynamite guy...
这是个有潜在攻击性 与威胁性的男人
...who can do anything he wants.
他能呼风唤雨
I mean, it's not my fault you keep putting yourself down.
这不是我的错，你一直自贬身价
- Oh, yeah? How? - Well, for starters...
-是吗？怎么说？ -首先
...you slouch all the time. Here, stand up straight.
你装作一副笨拙的样子 来，站直
There, that's better.
这样好多了
And get yourself a jacket with a vent and shoes that don't lace up...
替自己买件有开口的夹克 和不用带子束紧的鞋
...and a shirt with a little color or a pattern or something.
和一件有点颜色 或图形之类的衬衫
And a bow tie that doesn't look like a letter opener.
和一个看起来不像拆信刀的领结
All right, Lois. All right.
好吧，露薏丝，好吧
- We've been through this, haven't we? - Yes.
-我们讨论过这个了不是？ -是的
I know where this is all leading to.
我知道这一切的结局
And I'm sorry. I mean, I'm sorry...
我很抱歉、我很抱歉K
...but no matter how hard I try, I just...
不论我多努力尝试，我就是K
Just... Just never will be him.
就是永远不会变成他
Him who?
他是谁？
"Him who"? Him Superman.
“他是谁”？当然是超人
Now, I can't help the fact that you seem to think that you love him.
你似乎以为自己爱他 我无力改变这点
That's something I'll have to live with. But darn it, Lois, that's enough now.
这是我要忍受的地方 可恶，露薏丝，我受够了
Maybe I just can't stand the competition anymore.
或许我受够和他较劲了
And just maybe you've been the competition all along.
也许你一直以来就是那个对手？
Lois, I've never been particularly good at riddles.
露薏丝，我从不擅长猜谜
Let me make this one really easy for you.
让我把话说白一点
Why, with thousands of children potentially falling off something lethal...
全世界有无数孩子可能身陷危险
...all around the world, would Superman be in Niagara Falls today?
为什么超人今天会在尼加拉瀑布？
Why not the Grand Canyon?
为什么不是大峡谷？
- Ask the child's family. I'm sure they know. - Why is it always when I'm with you...
-问问孩子的家人，他们知道答案 -为何每次都是我和你在一起K
...until Superman appears? And then you seem to disappear.
直到超人现身？ 然后你似乎就消失了
- Very conveniently, it seems to me. - I was out for hot dogs. For Pete's sake...
-我一直觉得这巧合并不单纯 -天啊，我是去买热狗
When Superman appeared, I looked at that hot dog stand...
当超人来到现场时 我转头看热狗摊
...and you were gone.
你已经不在了
- I was... - Nowhere.
-我是K -消失无踪
I can't help it if I had to go to the...
我非去不可也没办法K
You are Superman, aren't you?
你就是超人，对吧？
Lois, look, we've been through these hallucinations of yours before.
露薏丝，我们以前就谈过 你的这种幻觉
Can't you see what you almost did?
你知道你差点做了什么事吗？
Throwing yourself off a building 30 stories high?
从30楼高跳下？
Can't you see the tragic mistake you almost made?
你知道那差点 铸成不幸的错误吗？
Yeah, I made a mistake. I made a mistake because...
对，我的确是犯了错，因为K
...I risked my life instead of yours.
我用的生命冒险 而不是你的
Lois, don't be insane.
露薏丝，别这样
And don't fall down because you're just gonna have to get up again.
别想假装倒下去 因为你还得站起来
Lois, now, don't be crazy now. Lois!
露薏丝，别闹了，露薏丝
It is you.
就是你
I guess I've known this for the longest time.
我想我一定知道很久了
You realize, of course...
你一定很清楚
...if you'd been wrong, Clark Kent would have been killed.
若猜错的话，克拉克肯特就死了
With a blank?
用空包弹也会死吗？
Gotcha.
骗到你了吧
A primitive sort of life form.
多么原始的生命啊！
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
Did you see what I did?
I have powers beyond reason here.
我拥有超凡的力量
We all have them, my dear.
我们三个都有，亲爱的
- Wow, this is your home? - No.
-这里就是你家 -不是
Actually, I live in the city, about three blocks from you.
事实上我住在城里 离你家三条街而已
No, this is a very special place for me.
这里对我是个很特殊的地方
I wanted you to see it.
我想让你看看这里
Listen, you warm enough?
你感觉够暖和吗？
I guess I should be freezing, but I'm not.
我应该觉得冷，但我并不冷
Good.
很好
Come on, let me show you.
来吧！我带你四处看看
I don't know.
不知道耶
From the look of them, I'll bet $ 10 they're from Los Angeles.
从他们的外表看来 十元赌他们来自洛杉矶
Hey, you hippies, get your butts off the road!
痞子！别挡路
I like the globe. It flashes red like our Krypton sun.
我喜欢那颗闪亮的红灯 就如同氪星的太阳
But not this irritating noise.
但不喜欢那恼人的噪音
Make way.
让开！
Did I hear right?
我听对了吗？
That son of a bitch give me an order?
那个混球对我下命令？
Duane, you take care of it.
杜安，让你来处理
（郡立警长）
Just what in the hell do you think you're doing here?
好吧！你以为你在做什么？
What is this symbol?
这是什么标志？
Do you follow another leader?
你追随其他领导人吗？
Follow the leader?
追随领导人？
Holy skunk sweat.
痛死了！
- All right. - A weapon of some sort.
-好吧K -这是什么武器？
How the hell did you do that?
你怎么办到的？
Jesus H. Christ.
我的老天爷啊！
- That was good. - I thought we might...
-那样很好 -我想或许我们K
...abandon the orange juice for once.
这次能够省略橘子汁
- Here, cheers. - Cheers.
-干杯！ -干杯！
Must be tough being Clark Kent, isn't it?
扮演克拉克肯特很辛苦吧？
No. No, I really...
不会
I really like it sometimes.
有时我还蛮喜欢的
Even though I do make a fool of myself.
虽然我是在愚弄自己
But, you know, if it weren't for him, I never would have met you.
但如果不是因为他K 我就不会认识你
But he is you.
但K他就是你
- It's kind of confusing. - Not to me, it isn't.
-真让人搞不清楚 -对我而言并不会
Everything's clear.
一切都很清楚
Until yesterday, a middle-American town that Middle America had forgotten.
直到昨天，我们一直遗忘 这座中部的中型美国市镇
But today, the population... Exaggerated reports put it at 123.
现在人口已达123人
- Has increased by three.
因为增加了3个人
And these three new arrivals bring destruction in their wake.
这三名新来的人马上带来毁坏
As I look west into East Houston this morning...
今天早上我向东休士顿看去
...I see a town gripped with fear. - Who's the guy?
-这座小镇充满了恐惧 -那是谁？
Get that guy. Follow the guy.
抓那个人，跟住他
Who's the big guy?
那个大个子是谁？
Okay, yeah, we've got a...
是的，我们遇上K
- You got that? - No.
-知道吗？ -不知道
- That's fine. - Try to wiggle it.
-没问题 -试着前后摆动一下
Who else is seeing this?
有哪些人能看到？
Well, with this satellite linkup, just about everybody. The whole planet.
利用卫星连线 全世界所有人都能看到
The whole planet Houston?
整个休士顿星吗？
Earth. The whole planet Earth.
是地球，整个地球
You may continue.
你可以继续转播
As the extraordinary story continues...
随着这桩意外事件的发展
- Enough of this man. - As this extraordinary...
-随着这桩意外事件K -这男人够了吧
If the whole planet is watching, let's show them something interesting.
如果全世界都在收看 能否让他们看些有趣划面？
Throw down your arms and surrender!
把武器放下投降
This is an order.
这是命令！
General Zod does not take orders. He gives them.
查德将军不接受命令 他是下命令的人
He was in the line of that fire and nothing happened to him.
他就在火线上 但是却毫发无伤
I haven't seen the likes of this since Superman.
我没有看过这种事 除了超人之外
Yes? Yes.
是的
The Newsbeat control room has informed me that a fleet of helicopter gunships is...
控制室已经通知我，有一队 武装直升机已经上路了
- Mr. President, sir, can't we...? - There's nothing anybody can do.
-总统先生，难道我们不能K -恐怕没有人有办法
They have such powers, nothing can stop them.
他们拥有强大的力量 什么都阻挡不了他们
Where's Superman?
超人在哪里？
Where is he? Why doesn't he do something?
他在哪里？ 为什么他不想想办法？
Fire again.
再发射
Look. They need machines to fly.
你看！他们要利用机器才能飞
- Banking now. - What bravery.
-降落了 -真是英勇啊！
Be nice to them, my dear. Blow them a kiss.
对他们好一点！送他们个飞吻
Rockets ready. Coming in on target. Wait, wait.
火箭准备就绪，瞄准目标中 等等K
We're out of control.
我们要下坠了
We're coming in, coming down. Can't control it!
我们要坠机了
We're coming down.
I win.
我赢了
I always win.
我每次都会赢
Is there no one on this planet to even challenge me?
全地球没有人敢向我挑战吗？
Come forward.
过来！
Your general wishes to speak.
将军阁下有话要说
I am General Zod, your ruler.
我是查德将军 你们的统治者
Yes, today begins a new order!
是的，今天以新的命令开始
Your lands, your possessions...
你们的土地，财产和生命
...your very lives will gladly be given in tribute to me.
全部都要献给我，查德将军
In return for your obedience...
为了回报你们的服从K
...you will enjoy my generous protection.
你们将享有我慷慨的保护
In other words, you will be allowed to live.
换言之，我允许你们活下去
So you are a general?
你是名将军K
And who is your superior?
谁是你的上级长官？
- I answer only to the president. - And he will answer to me.
-我只对总统负责 -而他将对我负责
Or all of his cities will end up like this one.
否则所有城市的下场 都将像这座小镇一样
Thousands of hours to create, and they defaced it in seconds.
花了数千小时才创造完成 几秒钟之内就已模糊不清
Imagine what they'll do to the world if we resist.
如果我们反抗 想想看他们会怎么做
The people of your planet are well-pleased with you, Kal-EI.
你的星球的人对你很满意，凯尔
You have served them faithfully, and they are grateful for it.
你很诚为他们服务，他们也很感激
And yet you have returned to reason with me once again.
但你居然又回来与我理论
My son, I have tried to anticipate your every question.
儿子，我一直尝试 预测你所有的问题，卡尔
This was one I'd...
我连想都没K
I'd hoped you would not ask.
我希望你不会问到这个问题
My attachment...
我的情感K
...the feelings which I have developed for a certain human being...
我对某位人类发展出的情愫
...have deeply affected me, Father.
已深深影响我，父亲
You cannot serve humanity by investing your time and emotion in one human being...
你投注原本该给所有人的 时间与情感，在一个人身上
...at the expense of the rest.
便无法服务全人类
- The concepts are mutally exclusive. - And...
-这两件事互不相容 -那么K
...if I no longer wish to serve humanity...
若我再也不愿为全人类服务K
Is this how you repay their gratitude?
你要这样回报他们的感恩吗？
By abandoning the weak, the defenseless, the needy...
丢下弱小的、无法自我保护的 有需要的人
...for the sake of your selfish pursuits?
只为了你自私的追求？
Selfish? After all I've done for them?
自私？在我为他们做了那么多之后？
Will there ever come a time when I've served enough?
我的服务 会有功德圆满的一天吗？
At least they get a chance for happiness.
至少他们有幸福的机会
I only ask as much, no more.
我也只要幸福，不需要更多
Yours is a higher happiness.
你的幸福层次更高
The fulfillment of your mission, an inspiration you must have felt.
你一定有感觉到 完成使命的鼓舞
You must have felt that happiness within you.
你心里一定体会过那种幸福
My son, surely you cannot deny that feeling.
儿子，你无法否定那种感受
No, I cannot...
不，我的确不能
...any more than I can deny the other, which is stronger in me, Father.
但也无法否定另外这股 更强的感觉，父亲
So much stronger.
它强烈的多了
Is there no way then, Father?
真的没有办法吗，父亲？
Must I finally be denied the one thing in life which I truly desire?
难道我将得不到 生命中唯一真正渴望之物？
If you will not be Kal-EI...
若你不当凯尔K
...if you will live as one of them...
若你当他们的一员K
...love their kind as one of them...
并如此爱他们的一员K
...then it follows that you must...
你必须变成
...become one of them.
一个普通人
This crystal chamber has in it the harnessed rays of the red sun of Krypton.
这座水晶舱中充满 氪星的太阳光
Once exposed to them...
一旦受到这些光线曝晒
...all your great powers on Earth will disappear.
你在地球上所有的力量
Forever.
都将永远消失
Once this is done, there's no going back.
因为一旦做了将无法回头
You will feel like an ordinary man.
你会感觉像个普通人
And you can be harmed like an ordinary man.
也会像普通人一样受伤
Think, Kal-EI.
三思啊，凯尔
I beg you.
我求求你
Father...
父亲K
...I love her.
我爱她
Think, Kal-EI.
要三思，凯尔
Come on. Come on.
快走K
Look out!
小心！
You are the one they call president?
你就是他们称为总统的人？
I am.
我就是
I see you are practiced in worshipping things that fly.
我认为你很崇敬飞行物
Good.
很好
Rise before Zod.
在查德面前不能坐着
Now, kneel before Zod.
现在到查德面前跪下
You are not the president.
你不是总统
No one who leads so many could possibly kneel so quickly.
一个统治那么多人的人 不会那么快就下跪
I am the man they are protecting.
我是他们保护的对象
I am the president.
我是总统
I'll kneel before you if it will save lives.
如果能救大家的命，我愿下跪
It will.
会的！
Starting with your own.
从救你自己的命开始
What a backward planet this must be...
这肯定是个落后的星球
...where the men wear the ribbons...
男人们穿戴缎带
...and the jewelry.
与珠宝
What I do now...
我现在做的
...I do for the sake of the people of the world.
都是为了全球人类
But there is one man here on Earth who will never kneel before you.
但地球上还有一个人 绝不会向你下跪
Who is this imbecile? Where is he?
那个笨蛋是谁？他在哪里？
I wish I knew.
我希望我知道
Oh, God.
天啊！
Zod.
查德
Hey.
喂
You're awfully quiet over there.
你真的很安静
Yeah, I was just thinking...
是的，我正在想K
...I can't believe what you've given up for me.
我不相信你竟会为我放弃一切
Are you kidding? I didn't do it for you, Lois, I did it for us.
你在开玩笑？那么做不仅为你 露薏丝，我是为了我们而做
See, I told you there'd be a hot dog place somewhere.
我告诉过你附近有家热狗店
Okay. It sure takes longer when you can't fly.
好吧！因为你不能飞 所以得花多一点时间
Hurry up.
快一点
- Come on. - Okay.
快点 好的
Come on, it's my treat. Come on.
来吧！我请客
Oh, boy, it's Mr. Wonderful.
天啊！是完美先生
Thank you.
哦？谢谢
- Do you have a men's room? - Yeah. Right in the corner.
-请问有男厕所吗？ -就在转角
- Want to sit down? - Yeah.
-想要坐下吗？ -好的
Hi, what would you folks like?
你们想吃点什么？
I'd like a cheeseburger with everything on it, and a Coke...
我要一客总汇起士汉堡 和一杯可乐K
...an order of fries and a side salad, please.
还要一份薯条及一份沙拉
- And for you, sir? - I'll think about it when I get back.
-你呢？先生 -等我回来再点
Right. That's one cheeseburger...
没问题，总汇起士汉堡
- Steak and eggs, over easy, coffee. - Can I have my Coke?
-牛排加蛋，只煎单面，咖啡 -我的可乐，谢谢
Coming right up.
马上来
- I'm sorry, that seat's taken. - It is now, sweetheart.
-对不起，这个位子有人坐 -就是现在，亲爱的
Can I buy you something to eat?
我能请你吃东西吗？
No, thank you.
不用了，谢谢
Excuse me. I think you're sitting in my seat.
对不起，你坐了我的位置
Your seat's in there, four-eyes.
你的位置在那边，四眼田鸡
Gee, I think perhaps somebody ought to teach you some manners, sir.
或许该有人教教你礼貌，先生
Yeah? Well, let me know when he comes in.
是吗？等他来了再告诉我
- Look, Clark, we can just... - Honey.
-我们只是想K -亲爱的K
Excuse me, sir, would you care to step outside?
对不起，先生 你愿意到外面去吗？
I said, excuse me, sir, would you care to step outside?
我说，请问先生 你愿意到外面去吗？
Now, listen, Rocky, your steak's coming right up.
听我说，你的牛排马上好
Keep it on the flame, Ron. This is just a minute steak.
让它在炉上热着 这件事只需要一分钟就解决
After you.
你先请
- Clark. - It's all right, honey.
-克拉克 -没关系的，宝贝
Clark!
克拉克！
You all right, fella?
你还好吗？
He's gonna be fine, just give me that.
他会没事的，把毛巾给我
- Clark? - Blood. It's my blood.
-克拉克？ -血！是我的血
I think maybe we ought to hire a bodyguard from now on.
我想K 或许从现在起，你该雇个保镖
I don't want a bodyguard. I want the man I fell in love with.
我不需要保镖 我要我爱上的那个人
I know that, Lois.
我知道，露薏丝
I wish he were here.
我希望他在这里
Clark.
克拉克
Boy, you just don't have enough sense to stay down, do you?
天啊！你还不打算罢手吗？
You... You... You are no good.
你K不是个好人
Settle down!
大家住手！
I don't like your meat anyway.
反正我不喜欢你的肉
Oh, God.
天啊！
Clark? Clark?
克拉克？K
Clark, can you get up?
你站得起来吗？
- All right. Come on. I got you. - Go slow. Go slow.
-没事的，我来扶你 -慢慢来
Try and get up in that chair.
试着坐到椅子上
- Sit down. - I'm all right. I'm all right.
-坐下 -我没事
Okay, everybody, he's all right. Just relax. We'll have some fresh coffee.
他没事，大家放轻松 我们还有些新煮的咖啡
I'll turn the box on.
我把电视打开
We interrupt this program for an urgent message...
本台节目暂时中断 播报一则紧急消息
...from the President of the United States.
由美国总统宣布
This is your president.
我是美国总统
On behalf of my country, and in the name of the other leaders of the world...
我代表美国 和世上其他领袖之名
...with whom I have today consulted...
以及今天我所谘询过的相关人员
...I hereby abdicate...
我在此宣布放弃K
...all authority and control over this planet...
我所有的权力 以及地球的控制权
...to General Zod.
让予查德将军
Zod.
查德
Only by strict compliance with all his directions...
唯有完全听从 他的命令才能活命
...will the lives of innocent millions be spared.
才得以拯救千百万无辜性命
Superman, can you hear me?
超人！你听到了吗？
- Superman, where...? - Who is this Superman?
-超人，你到底在哪K -谁是超人？
- You'll find out. And when you do... - Come to me, Superman, if you dare.
-你会知道的！到时候K -来找我，超人！如果你敢的话
I defy you.
我向你挑战
Come! Come and kneel before Zod.
过来！到查德面前下跪
Zod!
查德！
- Here? When? - When?
-这里？什么时候？ -什么时候？
Where the hell have you been, Mac? On a desert island?
你上哪儿去了？ 废弃的荒岛吗？
I have to go back.
我必须回去
You can't go back.
你不能回去
- There's no way now. - I have to.
-现在已经没办法了 -我必须去
I've gotta try, damn it. I've gotta try something, anything.
我一定要试试看！ 该死！我什么办法都要试
It's not your fault.
这不是你的错
You didn't know this was gonna happen.
你不知道会发生这种事
He knew.
他知道
I heard him.
我听到他说的
I just didn't listen.
但我却不在意
You're master of all you survey.
所有的调查都由你主导
And so I was yesterday.
我昨天也一样
And the day before.
还有前天也是
Hello, there.
嗨！你们好
Lex Luthor.
我是雷克斯路瑟
You've heard the name? The greatest criminal mind on Earth.
或许你们听过这个名字 我是地球上最伟大的罪犯
I told you this was a puny planet.
我告诉过你这只是个小星球
Wait just a moment.
请等一下！
Wait until you get to know me better. Will you, please?
等你们更了解我再说好吗？
Wait. Look, I can give you anything you want.
等等！你们想要什么 我都能提供
I can give you the brass ring...
我可以给你勇气 让你们有无限自由去残害K
...the unlimited freedom to maim, kill, destroy.
杀戮和毁灭
Plus, Lex Luthor's keen mind. Lex Luthor's savvy.
加上雷克斯路瑟敏锐的心灵 雷克斯路瑟的见解
Lex Luthor's career guidance. Lex Luthor's School of Better...
雷克斯路瑟是生涯导师 雷克斯路瑟是优质教师
We have all of this without you.
不用你，我们这些早就有了
You cannot bargain with what you don't have.
你不能用我们已有的东西协议
Magnificent One...
至尊
...what I am bargaining with is what you do not have.
我要用你没有的来协议
The son of Jor-EI.
乔尔的儿子
The son of Jor-EI?
乔尔的儿子？
I said that, didn't I?
我是这么说的，对吧？
Jor-EI, our jailer?
囚禁我们的乔尔？
No, Jor-EI, the baseball player.
不是，是棒球选手乔尔
Yes, Jor-EI, your jailer.
对啦，囚禁你们的乔尔
- The son of Jor-EI? On this planet? - Aye.
-乔尔的儿子？他在地球？ -对
Possibly you know him better by his nom de voyage...
或许你们比较熟悉他的化名
...or his name he travels under:
或是他用旅行用的名字
Superman.
超人
So this is Superman.
原来是超人
How do you know of Jor-EI?
你怎么认识乔尔？
My Fullness, as I explained to you before...
我是全心全意的 正如我先前向你解释的K
...I'm about the best there is.
我是地球上最棒的
Revenge.
复仇！
We will kill the son of our jailer.
我们将杀了狱卒的儿子
- Revenge. - Revenge! Now we're cooking.
-复仇 -复仇！我们正在进行
- He flies, then? - Constantly.
-他会飞吗？ -经常飞
- He has powers as we do? - Certainly.
-他的力量跟我们一样吗？ -当然
But, Magnificent One...
但是K至尊
...he's just one...
他只有一个人
...where you are three.
而你们有三个
- Or four, if you count him twice. - We will bring him to his knees.
-如果你把他算两次，就有四个 -我们会让他下跪
Wait!
等一下！
First, you must find him.
你们得先找到他才行
And Lex Baby is the only one who knows where he is.
唯有雷克斯宝贝知道他在哪里
What do you want?
你K想要什么？
Well, general...
将军K
...the world is a big place.
这个是个广大的星球
Thank goodness...
感谢上帝K
...my needs are small.
我的需求很小
As it turns out, I have this affinity for beachfront property.
海景的资产对我特别有吸引力
What do you want?
你K想要什么？
Australia.
我要澳洲
Hey.
嘿
Listen... Hey, come on, where are you...? Please!
听着，拜托！你去K？ 请停下！
Father?
父亲？
If you can hear me...
若你听得到我的话
...I failed.
我失败了
I failed you...
我让你失望
...I failed myself...
我让自己失望
...and all humanity.
也让全人类失望
I've traded my birthright...
我用与生俱来的权利K
...for a life of submission in a world that's now ruled by your enemies.
在由你的敌人统治的世界里 换取屈从的一生
There's nobody left to help them now...
已经没有人能帮助K
...the people of the world.
这个世界的人们
Not since I...
至少在我K
Father!
父亲！
Listen carefully, my son, for we shall never speak again.
好好听着，吾儿 这将是我们最后一次谈话
If you hear me now...
若你现在听得到我
...then you have made use of the only means left to you:
那你便使用到仅剩的能力之一
The crystal source through which our communications begun.
便是让我们开始沟通的水晶源头
The circle is now complete.
这个过程已然完整
You have made a dreadful mistake, Kal-EI.
凯尔，你犯了极大的罪过
You did this of your own free will...
你以自由意志决定
...in spite of all I could say to dissuade you.
枉顾我尽一切所能想说服你
I...
我K
Now you have returned to me for one last chance to redeem yourself.
现在你回到我面前 最后一次试着证明自己
This too finally I have anticipated, my son.
这部分最后我也预料到了，吾儿
Look at me, Kal-EI.
看着我，凯尔
Once before when you were small, I died...
当你小时候，我曾死过一次
...while giving you a chance for life.
是为了给你生命
And now, even though it will exhaust the final energy left within me...
现在，虽然这将用尽 我体内最后的能量K
Father, no.
父亲，不要
Look at me, Kal-EI.
看着我，凯尔
The Kryptonian prophecy will be at last fulfilled.
氪星的预言终于将被实现
The son becomes the father, the father becomes the son.
儿子变成父亲，父亲化为儿子
Farewell forever, Kal-EI.
永别了，凯尔
Remember me, my son.
要记得我，吾儿
My son.
吾儿
Father!
父亲！
Harold. Coffee, black, no sugar.
哈洛，黑咖啡，不加糖
Black, no sug... Yeah. Yeah.
黑咖啡，不加K
Who's paying, huh?
谁付钱啊？
No, no! There's three of them. That cockamamie general...
不，那里有三个人 有荒谬的将军
...and a big truck with hair on it and a broad that looks like the queen of the runway.
一台长头发的大卡车 和像伸展台皇后的女人
They can fly, they can see through things. Anything Superman can do, they can do.
他们能飞，能透视 超人能做的，他们都办得到
Where is he, anyway?
他人呢？
Maybe he hasn't heard about it yet, chief.
也许他还没有听到消息，老编
- Maybe... - Maybe he's just run out of guts.
-或许K -或许他的胆量用完了
- No sugar. And don't call me "chief." - He'll be here.
-不加糖，而且别叫我老编 -他会来的
- Lf there's any way at all, he'll be here. - Yeah, he'll be here.
-如果他有办法他一定会来的 -没错，他一定会来的
- What's going on? - I don't know.
-现在怎么样了？ -我不知道
- Hey, Charlie, you feel that? - Yeah.
-你感觉到了吗，查理？ -有
Sounds like an earthquake.
感觉好像地震
Oh, my!
我的天啊
- It's those three. - Stop!
-就是那三个 -停！
- Oh, my God, they're here now! - Oh, no!
-天啊，他们已经来了 -不好了
This is scary!
好恐怖
You all right, chief?
你没事吧？老编
Hi.
嗨！
You should see the White House. They'll be cleaning for months.
你们该看看白宫 得好几个月才能清干净
Lex Luthor.
我是雷克斯路瑟
Wouldn't you know it?
你猜不到吧？
This is the son of Jor-EI?
这是乔尔的儿子？
- No, but I bet you're a son of a... - Jimmy!
-不，但你一定是个K -吉姆！
You promised me the son of Jor-EI.
你答应给我乔尔的儿子
Yes, Your Grace.
没错，阁下
But what I've given you is the next best thing.
但是K 我所给你的是次好的
You just hold on to that little lady, and he'll be along.
抓住那位小姐K 他一定会来K
See, they have this relationship.
他们有这种特殊关系
She does all his public relations, and he gives her every exclusive.
她替他做公共关系 而他给她所有独家新闻
They're the best of friends. You know what I mean?
他们是最好的朋友 了解我的意思吗？
What an undemanding male this Superman must be.
这个超人还真随便
You could use a tuck here and there yourself, sister.
你也需要改进一点
Wait!
等一下！
- I'm sorry! - She lives for now.
-对不起！ -她暂时可以活命
Kill the rest, starting with him.
把其他人都杀了 就从他开始
Wait. Wait, wait, wait!
等等K
Wait. Wait.
等一下！等一下！
Don't you remember the White House? The Oval Room? We had a few laughs there.
还记得白宫吗？椭圆形办公室 我们曾有过欢笑
You ought to have that fixed.
你们一定要改一改
（白宫投降）
General...
将军
...haven't you heard of freedom of the press?
没听过媒体言论自由吗？
- Superman! - Superman, thank God.
-超人！ -感谢老天，是超人
I mean, get him!
我叫你去抓他！
Come to me, son of Jor-EI!
到我面前来，乔尔之子
Kneel before Zod!
到查德面前下跪
Watch out. You all right?
小心！你没事吧？
（白派瑞 总编辑）
Son of Jor-EI.
乔尔之子
We were beginning to think you were a coward.
我们开始以为你是个懦夫
I'm not a coward, Zod.
我不是懦夫，查德
It is extremely likely you are merely a fool.
你八成只是个笨蛋
Like father, like son.
有其父必有其子
Look out!
小心
Then die as you deserve to!
你该死就得死！
Come on, come on, Superman! Get him!
快！抓住他！
Man, this is gonna be good.
一定会没事的
Superman.
超人
- Hey, that's the chief's. - The chief's got it.
-那是老编的 -老编已经有了
What, you hit a woman?
什么，你打了女人？
Oh, my God! My baby!
天啊，我的小孩！
Help my baby!
救救我的宝贝
Thank you.
哦？谢谢
This Superman is nothing of the kind.
这个超人没什么了不起
- I've discovered his weakness. - Yes.
我已经发现他的弱点了 -是啊
He cares.
他关心
He actually cares for these Earth people.
他真的很关心地球人
- Like pets? - I suppose so.
-就像宠物一样？ -我想是吧！
I'll draw his fire...
我来分散他的注意力
...with some of my own.
用我自己的力量
What's happening to those cars?
那些车子怎么了？
Get out of the way!
别挡路！
（冷静一下！）
Superman.
超人
（请享用可口可乐）
Oh, thank you!
真是谢谢你
I never thought this thing would go the distance.
我没想到这事会持续这么久
No! Don't do it!
不要！别动手！
The people!
车上的人！
Throw it!
丢啊！
- Get away from there. Get away from there. - Let's help them out!
-别靠近那里，远离那个地方 -我们快去帮他们
- I got her. I got her. Don't worry. - He's dead.
-别担心，我去救她 -他死了
Superman is dead.
超人死了
They've killed Superman.
他们杀了超人
- He's dead. - Let's go get them!
-他死了 -我们去找他们报仇
- Come on, we'll show them! - I know some judo. Let's go!
-来，让他们知道我们的厉害 -我会空手道，上啊！
Come on!
来吧
I'm holding it, I'm holding it!
我抓住了！我抓住了！
What can you do if you can't see what's happening?
什么都看不到能做什么？
- Hold on! - Oh, my God!
-抓稳了 -天啊！
（不准进入）
（准备下地狱吧！ 世界末日到了！）
You can't leave us!
你不能丢下我们
So he is a coward after all.
那么，他毕竟是个懦夫
He's gone.
他走了
Come back, Superman!
回来！超人
Don't leave us!
别丢下我们！
He chickened out.
他临阵逃脱了
Phony!
骗子！
Superman didn't even do nothing.
超人什么都没做
Come on, let's go.
我们走
- There they are. - Get away from here. Jimmy.
-他们在那儿 -快走开，吉姆
Our victory is complete.
我们已经战胜了
The son of Jor-El has fled.
乔尔之子逃跑了
- Superman fled? - I don't believe you.
-超人跑掉了？ -我不相信你
You heard him. Three against one, you should've taken two ears and a tail.
你听到了，三对一 你大获全胜
- He fled in fear of us. - He'll be back.
-他被我们吓走了 -他会回来的
As long as he's alive, he's gonna try again.
只要他还活着，就会再试一次
- The next time, we will kill him. - The next time?
-下一次，我们会杀了他 -下一次？
The next time?
下一次？
What am I gonna do with you people?
我该拿你们怎么办？
I held up my end. I delivered you the blue boy.
我在这里等着超人出现
What do I get from my triple threat?
你们三位要如何回报我？
"Bow, yield, kneel." That kind of stuff closes out a town.
“鞠躬，屈膝，下跪” 这种事在这里不管用
Why do you say this to me when you know I will kill you for it?
你为什么这样对我说话？ 你明知我可以因此而杀你
Kill me? Lex Luthor?
杀我？雷克斯路瑟？
Extinguish the greatest criminal flame of our age?
杀掉本世代最伟大的罪犯
- Eradicate the only man on earth with... - Let me kill him!
-杀掉地球上唯一K -杀了他
- Superman's address?
超人的地址？
What more do you want? I can see the greed written on your face.
你还要什么？ 我看到你脸上写满贪婪
A small incentive, O Fullest One.
一个小奖励，最棒的
A mere bauble to jog the memory.
一样挑起回忆的小东西
What more?
还要什么？
Cuba.
古巴
I trust you are not wasting my time, Lex Luthor.
雷克斯路瑟 希望你不是在浪费我的时间
Of course not, Your Turbulence.
当然不是，难搞的大人
Show yourself, coward!
现身吧，懦夫
Son of a coward!
懦夫的儿子
I'm here, Zod.
我在这里，查德
- Let Miss Lane go, step inside. We'll talk. - No, don't, Superman!
-放莲恩小姐走，我们到里面谈谈 -不要，超人
Please don't listen to him. He's just...
别听他的，他只是个K
Stop.
停手
Your powers are identical to mine.
你的能力与我的相同
But we are three. We could tear you limb from limb.
但我们有三个人 可以把你五马分尸
Do it, Your Grace.
下手吧，将军大人
Just grab a leg and just make a wish.
抱只腿，许个愿
But you are victim to another fatal weakness...
但你是另一项致命弱点的受害者
...your compassion.
就是你的同情心
The death of others means more to you than your own.
对你来说 他人的死比你自己的更重要
Yes, with rare exceptions.
是的，但偶有例外
Your father condemned us to an eternal living death. Your fate will be the same.
你父亲让我们进人间炼狱永不得翻身 你的命运也将相同
You will live, Kal-EI, forever...
凯尔，你将永远活着
...as my slave. If not, then others will pay for your obstinate attitude.
做我的奴隶 否则他人将为你的固执付出代价
Innocent people, millions if necessary, beginning with this Lois person.
无辜的人，必要时可达上百万 就从这位露薏丝开始
- Don't, Superman, don't! - Stop it!
-超人，不要 -停手
All right, Zod.
好吧，查德
It's over.
一切都结束了
Your Grace, don't believe him! You don't know him the way that I do.
将军大人，别相信他 你不像我如此了解他
I sense the presence of Jor-El here.
我感觉到乔尔在这里
We will destroy this place.
我们会毁了这个地方
And then kill him.
然后杀了他
Him.
他
Him? Me?
是他还是我？
General, this is Lex Luthor.
将军大人，我是雷克斯路瑟
Remember...? I helped you through the tough times.
记得吗？在你失意时我帮过你
I filled your inside straight.
我让你充满力量
You came to me with nothing. I gave you Superman.
当初你双手空空来找我 而我给了你超人
Silence!
安静！
Well, look...
听好K
Guy's a clod.
这家伙真的很笨
You think you know people, right?
你还以为了解人们，是吧？
Promises were made, gifts were exchanged.
协议已经达成也交换了礼物
I gotta hand it to you, you know. You always told the truth.
我必须信任你 你说的都是实话
A guy always knew where he stood with you.
你很清楚谁跟你是同一阵线
Try to get them all into this molecule chamber here.
试着把他们骗进这个分子室
It takes away their powers, see...
它会夺走他们的力量
...and turns them into ordinary human beings.
使他们成为平凡的人类！
Now, if you could...
如果你能够K
- Don't go in there. It's a trap. - Luthor, you poisonous snake!
-不要进去！那是个陷阱 -你这个狡猾的家伙
That's a molecule chamber.
那是个分子室
It makes people like you into people like me.
它会把你们变成跟我一样
- You've done well, Lex Luthor. - I thought so.
-你做的很好，雷克斯路瑟 -我也这么觉得
Seize him.
抓住他
- Kill her. - No! Superman, no!
-杀了她 -不要，超人
All right! All right, leave her alone, Zod!
好啦，查德，别伤害她
You win.
你赢了
General, the crystal there activates the mechanism.
那颗水晶能够启动机器
Lex Luthor, ruler of Australia...
雷克斯路瑟，澳洲统治者
...activate the machine.
去启动机器
With your permission.
请你允许
And now, finally...
现在终于K
Kneel.
跪下
Take my hand...
握着我的手K
...and swear eternal loyalty to Zod.
发誓永远效忠查德
He switched it.
他转换了机器
He did it to them.
他将他们变弱了
The lights were on out here while he was safe in there.
我是说光线在外面 而他在里面很安全
Hey, you know something?
你知道吗？
You're a real pain in the neck!
你真的是个讨厌鬼
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
I knew you'd double-cross me, Luthor. A lying weasel like you couldn't resist.
我知道你会反叛我 狡猾如你忍不住会说谎
Who, me? Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吗？
Hey, I was with you all the time. That was beautiful.
我一直是跟你同阵线 真的好美
Did you see the way they fell into our trap?
你看到他们掉入陷阱的样子？
Too late, Luthor. Too late.
太迟了！太迟了！
Look. Look, Superman.
你看！是超人
I got a proposition for you.
我有个建议
Now, don't stop me till you've heard this...
不要阻止我 直到你听说这个K
...because I know I owe you one, but we're in the North Pole, right?
我知道我还欠你一次 但我们还在北极，对吧？
Look, Lois...
听着，露薏丝K
No regrets, okay? I did it.
我不后悔，好吗？ 我做到了
I got the man I loved to love me.
我让我爱的男人爱我
- Didn't I? - Oh, yeah.
-对不对？ -没错
Well, okay then. Those people need you.
好，就这样，那些人需要你
Do you think I don't understand that?
你以为我不懂吗？
We can still see each other, you know. I mean, all the time.
你知道的，我们依然可以见面 常常见面
But it just can't be...
但就是不能K
Just don't forget, that's all.
只要别忘记就好了
Don't ever forget.
永远别忘记
- Well, here we are. - Home sweet home.
-我们到了 -甜蜜的家
- See you at work in the morning. - Bright and early, huh?
-早上在办公室见 -朝气蓬勃，是吧？
- The same old Clark and the same old Lois. - Yup.
-原来的克拉克与原来的露薏丝 -没错
Except... maybe I won't be quite so mean to you from now on.
不过K 或许以后我会对你好一点
You don't have to worry.
你不用担心
Your secret's safe with me.
我会保守你的秘密
I know. I know that, Lois.
我知道，露薏丝
Well, there he goes, kid.
他走了，孩子
Up, up and away.
在天空飞翔
（号外！超人拯救人类 免于永恒统治）
（畅饮 可口可乐）
- No! - No!
-不要！ -不要！
- Hey, is Mr. White free? - On the telephone.
-白先生有空吗？ -他正在讲电话
- He's in conference at the moment. - Yeah, that's what he says.
-他现在正在开会 -对，这是他的说辞
（《星球日报》）
All right, give me three carbons of that.
好，给我三份副本
- Hi. - It's gonna be an insert in the paper.
-你好 -这将是报纸中的夹页
That's what they said.
他们是这么说的
Good morning. Hi.
早安，你好
Good morning, Lois.
早安，露薏丝
- Good morning, Lois. - Hi, Clark.
-早安，露薏丝 -你好，克拉克
Jeepers, I have seen some faraway looks in my time...
天啊，我看过不少人做白日梦
...but with that look, you might as well be on the North Pole.
但你这副德行 大概已飘到北极去了
The North Pole.
北极
No, that's too silly.
不，那太傻了
Did you ever feel like you knew something that was so important that...
你是否曾经觉得 你知道很重要的事，你得K
No, you never did.
不，你从来没有过
I mean, I feel like I'm sitting on the single most important story of my career...
我是说，我觉得手上有 整个生涯最重要的新闻
...and I can't remember what it is.
却记不得那是什么
Well, knowing you, it must have been about Superman.
以我对你的了解 那一定跟超人有关
Maybe how he saved the city or saved the world or saved the universe.
也许是他如何拯救这座城市 拯救地球，或拯救宇宙
Clark, Clark. Listen. Jealousy's really counterproductive.
克拉克K听我说 忌妒会让生产力下降
Now, there's some things that you can do too.
你也可以做点别的事
Oh, yeah?
是吗？
Really? Like what?
真的吗，做什么？
Get us a pizza.
帮我们叫披萨
- A pizza. Now? - Yeah, I'm hungry.
-现在要叫披萨？ -对，我饿了
Actually, I don't think Mr. White would like it if...
说真的，我想白先生要是发现 不会太高兴K
I'll pay for half of it, all right?
我出一半钱，好吗？
I'm going.
我去
Lois?
露薏丝？
You know, about the pizza?
你知道，披萨的事
It's okay. I'll pay for the whole thing.
没关系，我请客
You know, you're really super.
你知道吗，你人最好了
（超人今日休息！）
- Hey, Ron. - Yeah?
-你好，朗 -什么事？
Give me another plate of this garbage.
再给我一盘这种垃圾
Garbage? That's my number-one special, Rocky.
垃圾？这是最受欢迎的特餐
All right. Get me some more coffee too, will you?
好！再多给我一些咖啡好吗？
Gee, that's funny. I've never seen garbage eat garbage before.
哇！真有趣 我没看过垃圾在吃垃圾
Excuse me, sir. I think you're sitting in my favorite seat.
对不起，先生 你坐了我最爱的位子
Come and get it, four-eyes.
有本事过来抢！四眼田鸡
Now cool it, Rocky.
冷静点！
Take it easy, will you?
别激动！
I just had this joint fixed. It cost me a fortune.
这里我才刚修好 我可是花了一大笔钱
Oh, God!
天啊！
This order's to go.
外带！
（攻击吧）
I'm terribly sorry about all the damage, sir.
对于你的损失我感到很抱歉
I've been working out.
我一直在练健身
（自70年代此片拍摄以来 人们已有更高度的认知
不论是对皮草业 对动物造成的摧残
还是吸烟与二手烟 造成的健康危害
因此我将不宽恕 如本片描述般的
消费香烟与皮草 ―李察唐纳）
[ENGLISH]
[MANDARIN-R3]